# **Lucas Robitaille**

**FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER** 

Lucas.Robitaille@yahoo.com (512) 955-6706 Austin, Texas GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

# **Summary**

Web Developer with a knack for creative problem solving. I love working in teams and contributing to projects that make a positive impact in the world. Creating dynamic, responsive, and interactive web design is what I do best. I bring a unique perspective to web development because of my varied background and experiences.

## **Skills**

Front End: JavaScript ES6, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, NPM

Back End: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Additional Tools: Git, GitHub, Slack, Chrome Dev Tools, Heroku, Netlify, Zeit

# **Related Technical Experience**

THINKFUL 08/2019 - 11/2019

### Full-Stack Web Development Program / Engineering Immersion

- Learning industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Creating and deploying mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating every week with a senior web developer.

## **Projects Completed at Thinkful**

PUERH / CAFE | GitHub Repo | Live Site: This app helps users organize their pu'erh teas by adding collections and tasting notes.

- Built and deployed a scalable, modular software product.
- Integrate PUERH / CAFE api to allow users to access and display data.

Built with: React, Redux, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, and CSS

Hot Takes | GitHub Repo | Live Site: Keeps track of the 'hot takes' sports commentators have, to see who is the most reliable.

- Allow users to add commentators and takes, providing a platform to decide which commentators they should follow.
- Designed and developed the backend API, which persists end user data.

Built with: React, Redux, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, and CSS

**Travel TV Search** | GitHub Repo | Live Site: A search engine for finding travel tv shows based on an input location.

- Designed and developed the search feature to allow end users to discover travel TV shows.
- Integrated Google Maps API and TVMaze API to display results based on the end user's search.

Built with: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Google Maps API, and TVMaze API

## **Experience**

Giordani Swanger Ripp, LLP

Austin, Texas 09/2017 - 07/2019

Accounting Clerk

Prepared federal and state tax returns for individuals and businesses.

- Maintained bookkeeping in preparation for tax reporting across multiple entities.
- Created and edited invoices and issued them to customers through various means.
- Reconciled monthly firm credit card expenses, while tracking and analyzing the yearly budget.
- Produced guarterly and annual investment reports.

#### Simonds Homes Australia

Melbourne, Australia 03/2017 – 08/2017

#### Accounts Receivable Officer

- Investigated and followed up on unidentified payments.
- Invoiced customers daily, while maintaining a high level of accuracy and efficiency.
- Answered and resolved queries from both internal and external stakeholders.

# **Education**

### Colorado State University - Media Studies/New Media